# MD NAIMUL HOQUE

Website: mnhoque.com

(631) 431-0495

mdhoque@cs.stonybrook.edu LinkedIn:linkedin.com/in/mnhoque/

### **RESEARCH INTEREST**

My current research interests are algorithmic fairness, explainable AI, collaborative sense-making, and information visualization for the visually impaired person. In general, I am interested in projects that try to solve not only scientific problems but also have impacts on social well-being. I am particularly interested in the problems at the intersection of visual media (visual analytics, virtual reality, augmented reality), and HCI.

#### **EDUCATION**

New York, NY **Stony Brook University** Fall 2018 -

- Ph.D. in Computer Science, Oct 2019. CGPA: 3.86
- Graduate Coursework: Data Science Fundamentals; Algorithms; Probability and Statistics; Big Data; Visualization; Theory of Database Systems; Fundamentals of Networking.

Jan 2011 - Jun 2016 **Bangladesh University of Dhaka** 

- M.S. in Computer Science and Engineering. CGPA: 3.67
- B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering. CGPA: 3.60, In-major CGPA: 3.65.
- · Coursework: Programming Languages; Data Structure; Algorithms; Computer Architecture; Operating Systems; Artificial Intelligence; Software Engineering; Databases; Data Mining and Machine Learning;

#### **Publication**

- M.N. Hoque, D. Coelho, K. Mueller, Examining the Visualization Practices of Data Scientists on Kaggle, InfoVis Poster,
- M. M. Hassan, A. Adnan, A. M. Saleheen, M. N. Hoque, Understanding the Patterns of Crime Reports in a Popular Bangladeshi Newspaper, Companion of the 2018 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW 2018), NJ, USA. (Worked as a PI)
- M.N. Hoque, R.E. Fatima., M. Mandal, N. Saquib, Evaluating gender portrayal in Bangladeshi TV, Machine Learning for the Developing World, NIPS 2017 Workshop, Long Beach, CA, USA.
- M.S Rafid, M.M. Islam, M.N. Hoque, C.F. Ahmed, Reframing for Non Linear Dataset Shift, 18th Conference on Knowledge Extraction and Management (EGC 2018), Paris, France.
- M.N. Hoque, C.F. Ahmed, N. Lachiche., C.K. Leung, H. Zhang, Reframing in Clustering, 2016 IEEE 28th International Conference on Tools with Artificial Intelligence (ICTAI), San Jose, CA, USA.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Graduate Research Assistant Stony Brook University**

Summer 2019 -

 Projects: Visual causal model for transparent decision making; Collaborative sense-making through causal reasoning; Gender Bias in Media.

#### **Graduate Teaching Assistant**

#### **Stony Brook University**

Eastern University, Bangladesh

**Enosis Solutions, Bangladesh** 

**Fall 2018 – Spring 2019** 

· Courses: Data Structure; Probability and Statistics (Undergraduate); Machine Learning (Undergraduate).

## Courses: Introduction to Programming; Advanced Programming Lab; Data Structure;

Aug 2016 – Dec 2016

Jan 2017 - July 2018

JavaScript (AngularJS)

**Software Engineer** 

- Worked on a Health Analytics platform that uses multiple charts to show personalized data to a user.
- Worked on a backend dashboard interface for the same health analytics platform.

#### **AWARDS**

Lecturer

- Chairman's Fellowship (Fall 2018 Spring 2019), Stony Brook University.
- Organizing Excellence, 2017, Eastern University, Bangladesh, awarded for successfully organizing regional Math olympiad and several programming contests.

# Languages and Technologies

- C; C++; Java; Python; JavaScript; SQL;
- Flask; D3.js; MapReduce; Apache Spark; TensorFlow; Git;

Github: github.com/tonmoycsedu